Toma Kashamov

Technical writer

mobile: +359 889 452 410

email: toma.kashamov@gmail.com

Summary

Senior Technical and Content Writer with emphasis on IT and software. Experienced in blockchain technology and crypto trading, network security, Forex trading, online gaming, and VoIP. Prepared and supported web doc portals using tools such as Doc-as-code platforms, MadCap Flare, Wordpress knowledge bases, Zendesk, and Confluence.

Agile team player who has assisted different teams with technical content, including marketing, sales, support. Formidable player in intense delivery cycles with experience in coordinating deliveries, particularly in last-minute situations.

Stress survivor with curiosity beyond requirements, including interests in basic web programming technologies like HTML5, JavaScript, and CSS.

Highlights

- Technical and marketing content writer
- Cross-team communicator
- Tech-savvy expert
- Coordinator of multiple stakeholders
- · Creative thinker
- Team leader and mentor
- Self-organized, versatile deliverer
- Sparer of colleagues' time & efforts

Experience

Senior Technical writer - 01/2024 - 09/2024 in EnduroSat, Sofia, Bulgaria

- Preparation of user manuals, data sheets and configuration sheets for EnduroSat's satellite hardware modules, all written in LaTex and maintained in Git repos.
- Preparation and editing of user manuals for EnduroSat's software platforms, all written in MkDocs (docas-code platform) and maintained in Git repos.

Senior Technical & Content writer - 04/2023 to 08/2023 in Next Basket, Sofia, Bulgaria

- Preparation of Marketing & PR articles, preparation of Next Basket's knowledgebase from scratch (on Hubspot).
- Setup of tech writers' work processes in Jira to fit the SCRUM/Agile approach for deliveries.

Senior Technical writer - 06/2021 to 10/2022 in Qredo, Sofia, Bulgaria

• Preparation of technical documentation for Qredo's APIs and pluggable components, including API reference guides, developer guides, technical papers.

Senior Technical writer - 03/2017 to 06/2021 in Axway, Sofia, Bulgaria

- Preparation of technical documentation for Axway's SecureTransport platform, an enterprise-level MFT (Managed File Transfer) solution, including administrator guides, user guides, release notes, developer guides, etc. and maintaining documentation up to date with releases of patches and new versions.
- Setup of complex tech writers' work processes in Jira to fit the SCRUM/Agile approach for deliveries.

Senior Technical writer - 12/2015 to 02/2017 in Secure Group Labs, Sofia, Bulgaria

• Preparation and updating of technical documentation for the product line of encrypted solutions for mobile devices, including the complete revamp of the company's WordPress Heroic Knowledgebase; and Inline Manual webhelp documentation tool for interactive web tutorials.

Senior Technical writer - 12/2014 to 12/2015 in Naxex, Sofia, Bulgaria

• Preparation and updating of technical documentation for the Naxex' FOREX trading platform, including release notes; user guides (including in both Webhelp and print format).

Senior Technical writer - 09/2012 to 08/2014 in TradoLogic, Sofia, Bulgaria

• Preparation and updating of technical documentation for the Tradologic's binary options trading platform, including release notes; user guides; integration guides; (API) reference guides.

Sales manager and technical writer - 04/2012 to 08/2012 in Zoiper, Sofia, Bulgaria

- In charge of enterprise customers who require technically advanced aid for the purchase, customization, and deployment of VoIP software, mostly regarding Zoiper softphone.
- Updated existing technical documentation plus created and edited templates for tech support responses.

Technical writer - 11/2010 to 08/2011 in ProSyst, Sofia, Bulgaria

 Preparation and updating of user and developer guides for home automation modules of Prosyst's proprietary OSGi-based platform; most documentation published as web content.

Technical writer - 05/2008 to 09/2010 in Playtech, Sofia, Bulgaria

• Preparation and updating of technical documentation for the online Bingo and Poker gaming platforms, including release notes, user guides, reference guides, and API reference guides.

Technical writer and marketing content writer - 09/2006 to 05/2008 in Zoiper, Sofia, Bulgaria

- Preparation and updating technical documentation for Zoiper softphone, including user manuals, API reference guides, provisioning documentation, etc.
- Preparation and publishing of news articles, press releases and other marketing documentation; website content; search engine optimization (SEO).

Note: This list of past jobs is not the complete. For the sake of brevity, it only includes roles that are pertinent to IT, software and technical or marketing content.

Education

1997-2004 - Master's Degree, Electrical Engineering; Technical University, Sofia

1992-1996 - 127th High School, Sofia

1991-1992 - Junior High School 190, New York City, USA

IT skills

This comprehensive list is not entirely complete but rather provides useful insight.

| Software Type | Software Name | Skill Level |
|---|---|--------------------|
| Operating Systems | MS Windows Ubuntu, Linux mint, Mac OS, Android | Advanced Medium |
| Office Tools | MS Office: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Visio Open Office suite | Advanced |
| | | Advanced |
| Document Portals | MS Sharepoint, WordPress Heroic Knowledgebase, | Medium to |
| | Zendesk, Hubspot, Confluence | Advanced |
| Authoring Tools (WYSIWYG) | MadCap Flare | Advanced |
| | DrExplain | Advanced |
| | Inline Manual | Medium |
| Authoring Tools (Doc-as-code) | Slate | Medium |
| | Docusaurus | Medium |
| | MkDocs | Advanced |
| | LaTeX | Medium |
| ScreenCapturing Tools | TechSmith SnagIt, MS snippet tool, ScreenRec, OBS | Advanced |
| | Studio, Greenshot | |
| Graphics Editor | Adobe Photoshop | Basic |
| | Paint.NET | Medium |
| | Techsmith Snagit Editor | Advanced |
| Programming Languages / Frameworks | HTML, XML, JSON, CSS, W3.CSS, Bootstrap, JS, JQuery | Medium |
| | PHP, Java, Python, C++, Delphi, Pascal* | Basic |
| | *Limited use and experience with these languages. | |
| Source Control | Git, CVS, SVN | Basic to |
| | | Medium |
| Collaboration & Issue tracking software | JIRA, TFS, Bugzilla, ClickUp, Kanbanize | Basic to |
| | | Medium |

Personal data

Year of birth: 1978Citizenship: Bulgarian

• Current location: Sofia, Bulgaria

Human Languages

- Bulgarian mother tongue
- English excellent certificate from 1st English Language High-School in Sofia, Bulgaria
- Spanish basic to medium level
- Russian basic
- German basic

Miscellaneous

Some unmentioned previous roles include:

- (2004-2006) Translator of English books (English to Bulgarian) for Riva Publishers: "Mr. Nice" by Howard D. Marks and "Adept" by Robert Finn
- (1996-2010) Two-way freelance translator (English and Bulgarian) for different technical documentation, including user guides and specifications for various technology products; translations of legal documentation; translations and composing of website content
- (2004-2008) Two-way freelance translator (English and Bulgarian) for Butex Translations agency, Bulgaria

Personal interests

- · acoustic and electric guitar player
- multi-sports enthusiast
- poet, writer and copywriter
- basic web programmer

- crypto proponent and occasional trader
- standup comedy fanatic
- casual gardener
- eco-friendly lifestyle evangelist